Register of the Sir Karl Raimund Popper Papers, 1928-1995
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS I, 1928-1986
  - The Self and Its Brain: An Argument for Interactionism (with John C. Eccles), 1977
    - English version
      - First edition, 1977
        - Research material (Box 181, Folder 1)
        - Notes
          - General (Folder 2-9)
          - General (Box 459, Folder 19)
          - 1952-1953 (Box 181, Folder 10-11)
          - 1952-1953 (Box 182, Folder 1-2)
          - 1970 (Folder 3)
          - 1974
            - April-May (Folder 4)
            - September ( re Part III) (Folder 5)
            - October-November (Folder 6)
          - 1975 (Folder 7-8)
          - 1976 (Folder 9-11)
          - 1977 (Comments about 'emergence discussion' after telephone conversation of, January 13) (Folder 12)
          - To John C. Eccles (Folder 13)
          - By Jeremy F. G. Shearmur (Folder 14)
          - Re "Digression: The Body-Mind Problem" (Folder 15)
        - Holograph (in part typescript) (Box 183, Folder 1-2)
        - Typescript (in part holograph)
          - Preliminary version (Folder 3-5)
          - Preliminary version (Box 184, Folder 1)
          - Miscellaneous draft pages, including an outline entitled "Indeterminism: Openness of Physical Theory" (also entitled "The Incompleteness of Physical Theory") (Folder 2)
          - Part I (Karl Popper's contribution)
            - Table of contents (Folder 3)
            - Acknowledgements (Folder 4)
            - Preface. (Folder 5-7)
              Includes letter from John C. Eccles, 1977 January 18
            - Introduction
              - General (Folder 8-9)
              - "An Historical Introduction to the Problem of Matter and Mind: Introductory" (draft only - not for publication) (Folder 10)
            - Complete set (Folder 11)
            - Fragments (Box 185, Folder 1-10)
            - Fragments (Box 186, Folder 1-9)
            - Fragments (Box 187, Folder 1-5)
            - Fragments (Box 188, Folder 1-7)
            - Fragments (Box 189, Folder 1-7)
            - Fragments (Box 190, Folder 1-12)
            - Fragments (Box 459, Folder 20-21)
            - Miscellaneous pages (Folder 22)
            - Miscellaneous pages (Box 190, Folder 13)
            - Insertions (Box 191, Folder 1-5)
            - Suggested corrections (Folder 6)
            - Bibliography (Folder 7)
          - Part II (John C. Eccles' contribution)
            - Table of contents (Folder 8)
            - Chapter 1 (Folder 9)
            - Chapter 2 (Folder 10)
            - Chapter 3 (Folder 11)
            - Chapter 4 (Folder 12)
            - Chapter 5 (Folder 13)
            - Chapter 6 (Folder 14)
            - Chapter 7 (Folder 15)
            - Chapter 8 (Folder 16)
            - Bibliography (Folder 17)
          - Part III (Dialogues)
            - Complete set (Box 192, Folder 1-3)
            - Complete set (Box 193, Folder 1)
            - Fragments (Folder 2-6)
            - Fragments (Box 194, Folder 1-13)
            - Fragments (Box 459, Folder 23)
            - Miscellaneous pages and additions. (Box 194, Folder 14)
              Includes queries and notes
            - Suggested corrections (Box 195, Folder 1)
            - Suggested corrections (Box 459, Folder 24)
            - As sent to the printer (Box 195, Folder 2-3)
            - Bibliography (Folder 4)
        - Proofs
          - Introductory pages (Box 196, Folder 1)
          - Part I
            - Complete set (Folder 2-4)
            - Fragments (Folder 5)
            - Fragments (Box 197, Folder 1-11)
            - Additions (Folder 12)
          - Part III
            - General (Folder 13)
            - General (Box 198, Folder 1-4)
          - Diagrams (Folder 5)
          - Bibliography (Folder 6)
          - Index (Folder 7)
        - Correspondence, 1972-1978 (Folder 8)
        - Promotional material, including dust jacket (Folder 9)
        - Reviews
          - General (Box 199, Folder 1-4)
          - General (Box 459, Folder 25)
          - With accompanying letters from David M. Armstrong, Andrew G. Bjelland, and Peter B. Medawar (Box 199, Folder 5)
          - Barlow, Horace B. (Folder 6)
          - Mandler, George. (Folder 7)
            Includes John C. Eccles' letter to the editor
          - Sutherland, Stuart. (Folder 8)
            Includes John C. Eccles' letters to the editor
          - Warnock, G. J. (Folder 9)
            Includes Karl Popper's reply
        - Corrections for forthcoming editions and translations (Box 200, Folder 1-2)
      - First corrected printing, Proofs, 1981. (Folder 3)
      - Paperback edition, 1984
        - Postscript. Holograph (Folder 4)
        - Corrected copy of printing, 1981 (Folder 5-7)
      - Second corrected printing, Proofs, 1985. (Folder 8)
    - Chinese version of Chapter 2 ("Worlds 1, 2, 3"), Philosophical Problems in the Natural Sciences ( Ziran Kexue Zhexue Wenti Conkan ), Printed copy, 1980. (Box 459, Folder 26)
    - Italian version, Review, 1981. (Box 200, Folder 9)
    - German version, 1982
      - Corrections
        - To English edition proofs (Folder 10)
        - To translation (Folder 11)
      - Proofs (Folder 12)
      - Proofs (Box 201, Folder 1-6)
      - Proofs (Box 202, Folder 1-3)
      - Promotional material (Folder 4)
      - Reviews (Folder 5-7)
  - "Some Remarks on Panpsychism and Epiphenomenalism," Dialectica, 1977
    - Typescript (Folder 8-9)
    - Proofs (Folder 10)
    - Spanish translation, Teorema, Printed copy, 1978. (Folder 11)
  - Interview (by mail) used for an article by John H. Douglas entitled "The 2 Cultures Twenty Years Later," Science News, Typescript answer to one of the three questions, printed copy, and correspondence, 1976, 1977 February 19. (Folder 12)
  - "In Defense of Optimism: An Interview with Sir Karl Popper" (by Shari Steiner), intended for publication in the New York Times Magazine, 1977 June
    - Notes (Folder 13)
    - Holograph (Folder 14)
    - Typescript (Folder 15)
    - Correspondence (Folder 16)
  - "Unsere Pflicht ist, optimistisch zu sein," Spiegel, ca. July. Interview. Holograph, typescript, and proofs, 1977 (Folder 17)
  - "Natural Selection and the Emergence of Mind," Darwin lecture, Darwin College, Cambridge, England, 1977 November 8.
    - General (Box 203, Folder 1)
    - Notes and outline. (Folder 2)
      Includes typewritten notes of November 11
    - Holograph
      - General (Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous pages (Folder 4)
    - Typescript (in part holograph)
      - Undated (Folder 5-11)
      - October 13 (Folder 12)
      - October 17 (Folder 13)
      - October 21 (Folder 14)
      - October 24 (Folder 15)
      - October 25 (Folder 16-17)
      - October 26 (Folder 18-19)
      - October 27 (Box 204, Folder 1)
      - October 28 (Folder 2)
      - October 31 (Folder 3)
      - November 1 (Folder 4)
      - November 2-5 (Folder 5)
      - November 6 (Folder 6)
      - November 7 (Folder 7)
      - November 8 (Folder 8)
      - November 10 (Folder 9-10)
    - Version for publication in Dialectica, 1978
      - Typescript (Box 205, Folder 1-2)
      - Proofs (Folder 3)
      - Printed copy (Folder 4)
      - Chinese translation, Philosophical Problems in the Natural Sciences ( Ziran Kexue Zhexue Wenti Conkan ), Printed copy, 1980. (Box 459, Folder 27)
    - Subsequent version of essentially the same speech. Typescript (Box 205, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous pages (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence
      - British Broadcasting Corporation (David Paterson), 1977-1978. (Folder 7)
        Includes typescript edited by David Paterson for a radio broadcast
      - Cambridge University Press (Jeremy Mynott), 1977 (Folder 8)
      - Finley, Moses I., 1976-1979 (Folder 9)
      - Interdisciplinary Science Reviews (Anthony R. Michaelis), 1976-1977 (Folder 10)
  - "On the Possibility of an Infinite Past: A Reply to Whithrow," British Journal for the Philosophy of Science, Printed copy, 1978. (Folder 11)
  - "Three Worlds" (early drafts entitled "Mind-Body Interaction and the Reality of World 3"), The Tanner Lecture on Human Values, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1978 April 7.
    - Research material (Box 206, Folder 1)
    - Notes (Folder 2)
    - Holograph (in part typescript) (Folder 3-4)
    - Typescript
      - Annotated typescript of Romanes lecture of, 1972 (Folder 5)
      - Before, April 7 (Folder 6-9)
      - As read on, April 7 (Folder 10)
    - Version for publication in The Michigan Quarterly Review
      - Typescript
        - General (Folder 11-14)
        - Footnotes by Jeremy F. G. Shearmur (Folder 15)
        - Suggested corrections by Troels Eggers Hansen (Folder 16)
      - Proofs (Box 207, Folder 1)
      - Printed copy (Folder 2)
    - Version for publication in The Tanner Lectures on Human Values
      - Typescript (Folder 3-5)
      - Printed copy (Folder 6)
    - Revised version (Folder 7-9)
    - Miscellaneous pages (Folder 10)
  - Speech upon receiving an honorary doctorate from the Universitat Wien, Vienna, Austria, 1978 April 12
    - General (Folder 11)
    - Holograph and typescript (Folder 12)
    - Correspondence with Kurt Komarek, Chr. Mayer, Herbert Zdarzil, Engelbert Broda, Herbert Pietschmann, and Karl Foltinek (Folder 13)
  - Speech upon receiving the Dr. Karl Renner-Stiftung Prize, Vienna, Austria, 1978 April 14
    - General (Folder 14)
    - Holograph and typescript (Folder 15)
    - Correspondence with Leopold Gratz, Gertrude Frohlich- Sandner, and Karl von Schwarzenberg (Folder 16)
  - "Interaction and The Reality of World 3," Paper, The European Forum Alpbach 1978, Knowledge and Power: Problems of Legitimacy in Culture and Society, Alpbach, Austria. See also CORRESPONDENCE, Osterreichisches College, 1978 August 25.
    - General (Box 208, Folder 1)
    - Notes (Folder 2)
    - Holograph (in part typescript) (Folder 3)
    - Typescript
      - (as read)., August 25 (Folder 4)
        Includes corrected retyped pages
      - After, August 25. (Folder 5)
        Includes copy for distribution
      - Miscellaneous pages (Folder 6)
    - Joseph Agassi's question put to Karl Popper. Holograph (Folder 7)
    - Paper of John C. Eccles. (Folder 8)
      Includes other writings of his on brain-mind theories
    - Introductory remarks and seven theses presented at seminar (similar to first part of paper). Typescript (Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with Otto Molden (Folder 10)
    - Clippings (Folder 11)
    - German translation (for publication of the forum's proceedings). Typescript (Folder 12)
  - Letter to the editor, Die Presse, Holograph, typescript, printed copy, and correspondence, 1978 September 16-17. (Folder 13)
  - "Some Reflections on the Prehistory of Our Western Universities and on Their Present Crisis," Speech, University of Guelph, Guelph, Ontario, Canada, 1978 October 5.
    - General (Folder 14)
    - Holograph and notes (Folder 15)
    - Typescript
      - First draft (in part holograph) (Folder 16)
      - As read on, October 5 (Folder 17)
      - Corrected and sent to Thomas W. Settle (Folder 18)
      - Final versions A and B (Folder 19)
    - German translation (for publication in Reclam ). (Folder 20)
      Includes correspondence, 1979
  - Notes re Socrates' political views, Typescript, 1978 October 11. (Folder 21)
  - Paper, American Philosophical Association, Hilton Hotel, Washington, D.C., Notes, holograph, and typescript, 1978 December 28. (Folder 22)
  - Die beiden Grundprobleme der Erkenntnistheorie, 1979
    - Research material (Box 209, Folder 1)
    - Notes, including notes by Jeremy F. G. Shearmur (Folder 2-3)
    - Typescript (in part holograph).
      - Preliminary draft (Folder 4-5)
      - Preliminary draft (Box 210, Folder 1-9)
      - Final draft (Box 211, Folder 1-7)
      - Final draft (Box 212, Folder 1-7)
      - Final draft (Box 213, Folder 1-4)
      - Final draft (Box 214, Folder 1-3)
      - Final draft (Box 215, Folder 1-9)
      - Final draft (Box 459, Folder 28)
      - Diagrams (Box 215, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous pages (Folder 11)
    - Corrections
      - General (Folder 12)
      - Editor's afterword (Folder 13)
    - Proofs
      - General (Folder 14-16)
      - General (Box 216, Folder 1-6)
      - General (Box 217, Folder 1-2)
      - Index (Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous pages (Folder 4)
      - Corrected for intended English and Italian editions (Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Troels Eggers Hansen and Jeremy F. G. Shearmur, 1975-1980. (Folder 6)
    - Reviews
      - General (Box 218, Folder 1)
      - Del-Negro, Walter von. (Folder 2)
        Includes correspondence between Karl Popper and Troels and Margit Hansen
    - English translation. Typescript
      - Introduction by R. N. D. Martin (checked by J. D. Graham), (1978) (Folder 3)
      - Introduction and Chapter 5, by Sheilagh C. Ogilvie, (1978) (Folder 4)
  - "Is It True What She Says About Tarski?" Philosophy, (in answer to Susan Haack, "Is It True What They Say About Tarski?"). Typescript, proofs, printed copy, and correspondence, 1979 (Folder 5)
  - "On the Part Played by Some Empirical Refutations in the History of Physics," Paper for a seminar or conference, The Falsifications in the History of Physics, 1979 February 11 or 12.
    - General (Folder 6)
    - Research material (Folder 7)
    - Notes (Folder 8)
    - Holograph (Folder 9)
    - Typescript
      - 1979 (Folder 10-12)
      - 1979 (Box 459, Folder 29)
      - 1981 August (Box 218, Folder 13)
    - Letter from Michael Redhead, 1980 September 11 (Folder 14)
  - "Karl Popper," Eton College Chronicle, Interview. Printed copy, 1979 March 2. (Folder 15)
  - "The Revolution in Our Idea of Knowledge," Speech, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C., 1979 March 26.
    - Research material (Box 219, Folder 1)
    - Notes
      - General (Folder 2)
      - For slides and diagrams (Folder 3)
    - Outline and holograph (complete) (Folder 4)
    - Holograph fragments and miscellaneous pages (Folder 5)
    - Typescript
      - Early draft (Folder 6-9)
      - March 20 (Folder 10-11)
      - March 20 (Box 220, Folder 1-3)
      - March 23 (Folder 4)
      - March 26 (Folder 5-7)
      - March 29 (Folder 8-10)
      - April 2 (Folder 11-12)
      - Long version. (Box 221, Folder 1-3)
        Includes notes and other writings
      - Short version (as delivered and sent to Doubleday) (Folder 4-7)
      - Miscellaneous pages (Folder 8)
    - Appendix. Typescript and holograph (Folder 9)
    - Correspondence (Folder 10)
  - "Special Relativity and Moving Clocks," Paper (Princeton Symposium?). Holograph and typescript, 1979 May. (Box 222, Folder 1)
  - Contributions to the Third C.H. Boehringer Sohn Symposium, Structure in Science and Art, Kronberg, Taunus, Germany, 1979 May 2-5
    - "A Real EPR Experiment." Speech. Printed copy, Structure in Science and Art (Folder 2)
    - Discussion
      - Notes (Folder 3)
      - Typescript. (Folder 4-5)
        Includes a paper by Richard L. Gregory
      - Proofs (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Peter B. Medawar and Julian H. Shelley (Folder 7)
  - Letter to the editor, Eton College Chronicle, Printed copy, 1979 May 25. (Box 459, Folder 30)
  - Interview, Frankfurt am Main, Germany, Typescript, and letter from Norbert Caspar, 1980 April 19, which, 1979 June 6. (Box 222, Folder 8)
    Includes the typescript of the Sudfunk radio broadcast of 1979 December 10 entitled "Idee sterben lassen anstelle unserer selbst," based on this interview
  - "Wissen und Nichtwissen," Speech upon receiving an honorary doctorate from the Johann Wolfgang Goethe-Universitat, Frankfurt am Main, Germany, 1979 June 8.
    See also Incremental Material, box 487, folder 2, for introductory remarks
    - Holograph (Folder 9)
    - Typescript
      - First draft, 1979 May 17 (Folder 10)
      - Sent to Gerd Fleischmann to be retyped, 1979 May 22 (Folder 11)
      - Corrected retyped version (Folder 12)
    - Proofs and printed copy, 1980, corrected for subsequent use in Auf der Suche nach einer besseren Welt, 1984 (Folder 13)
    - Correspondence with Gerd Fleischmann, E. Wurdack, Christoph von Mettenheim, and Ernst Topitsch (Folder 14)
  - Interview for L'Opinione, 1979 July 24 (date on which answers to L'Opinione 's questions were sent). Typescript and correspondence with Salvatore Carruba (Folder 15)
  - "Schopferische Selbstkritik in Wissenschaft und Kunst," Opening address, Salzburg Festival, Salzburg, Austria, 1979 July 26.
    - General (Box 223, Folder 1)
    - German text
      - Typescript (Folder 2)
      - Proofs. (Folder 3)
        Includes holograph and typescript insertions
      - Printed copy (Folder 4)
      - Printed copy (Box 459, Folder 31)
      - Correspondence with Renate Buchmann (Residenz Verlag) and letter to the translator (Box 223, Folder 5)
    - English text
      - Typescript (Folder 6)
      - Printed copy
        - Salzburger Festspiele 1979: Offizielles Programm (Folder 7)
        - Encounter (slightly revised version). (Folder 8)
          Includes proofs and letter from Bryan Healing
    - Correspondence with Wilfried Haslauer, Dr. Mittermayr, Bernhard Stillfried, F. G. Friedmann, Friedrich Pangratz, Gerhard Neureiter, and Monika Kalista, 1978-1979 (Folder 9)
    - Clippings (Folder 10)
  - "Uber die sogenannten Quellen der menschlichen Erkenntnis," Speech upon receiving an honorary doctorate from the Universitat Salzburg, Salzburg, Austria, 1979 July 27.
    - Notes and holograph (Folder 11)
    - Typescript (Folder 12)
    - Printed copy, Das Fenster (Folder 13)
  - Review of Edward J. Steele, Somatic Selection and Adaptive Evolution, Times Literary Supplement, Typescript, 1979 November 23. (Folder 14)
  - "The Chronology of the Neutrino Experience," Holograph., 1980? (Folder 15)
  - "The Experiment (Argument) of Einstein, Podolsky and Rosen and the Realistic Interpretation of Quantum Mechanics,", 1980
    - Notes (Folder 16)
    - Holograph. (Folder 17)
      Includes holograph of Jean-Pierre Vigier
  - Preface to Winfried Moewes, Grundfragen der Lebensraumgestaltung, 1980
    - Holograph, typescript, and proofs (Folder 18)
    - English translation. Holograph and typescript (Folder 19)
  - "Uber den Zusammenprall von Kulturen," Speech, Austrian Expatriates Society, Vienna, Austria, 1980 May 14.
    - Holograph (Box 224, Folder 1)
    - Typescript (Folder 2)
    - Printed copy, 25 Jahre Staatsvertrag. (Folder 3)
      Includes correspondence with Eva Janko
    - Correspondence with Fritz P. Molden (Folder 4)
    - Clipping (Folder 5)
    - English translation. Typescript (Folder 6)
  - "Kritische Theorie," ? Contribution to a symposium, Die Wissenschaftsmethodische Grundlegung der Demokratieforschung, Wurzburg, Germany. Notes and correspondence with Lothar Bossle, 1980 July (Folder 7)
  - "Falsifizierbarkeit" (essay for the Handlexicon fur Wissenschaftstheorie ), 1980 August
    - Notes (Folder 8)
    - Holograph (Folder 9)
    - Typescript. (Folder 10)
      Includes letters from Gunnar Andersson
  - "Notes on Alternative Implications of Possible Outcomes of Recent Quantum-Mechanical Experiments," Notes and typescript, 1980 August. (Folder 11)
  - Letter to the editor, New Scientist, (in response to an article by L. Beverly Halstead), 1980 August 21
    - Holograph, typescript, and printed copy. (Folder 12)
      Includes cover letter and further correspondence with the editor (Michael Kenward), as well as notes by Harvey Fields
    - Article by L. Beverly Halstead, 1980 July 17. (Folder 13)
      Includes letter to Karl Popper
    - Article by John Little, (in response to the article by L. Beverly Halstead)., 1980 September 4 (Folder 14)
      Includes letter from Karl Popper
    - Correspondence with Colin Patterson and Norris D. McWhirter (Folder 15)
  - "Der wichtigste Beitrag seit Aristoteles," Wissenschaft aktuell, Interview on Kurt Godel and the Vienna Circle conducted by Peter Weibel in August 1978 in Alpbach, Austria. Proofs, printed copy, and correspondence, 1980 September. (Folder 16)
  - "Three Important Points against Probabilistic Induction," Holograph, 1980 September 26. (Folder 17)
  - "The Present Significance of Two Arguments of Henri Poincare," Speech, European Academy of Arts, Sciences, and Humanities, Paris, France, 1980 November 14.
    - Holograph (Folder 18)
    - Typescript (Folder 19)
    - Printed copy
      - Fundamenta Scientiae (Folder 20)
      - Essays in Scientific Philosophy. (Folder 21)
        Includes typescript revised for this publication
    - Summary. Typescript (Folder 22)
    - Correspondence with Raymond Daudel, 1980-1981 (Folder 23)
  - "Inflation vs. Kapazitat - Altes Geld vs. neues Geld," Holograph, 1980 December. (Folder 24)
  - "When Does (How Could) Signalling Turn into Description?" (based on the ideas of Irene Papadaki), Holograph and typescript, ca. 1981. (Folder 25)
  - "Axiom System for Probability Without Negation or With Intuitionist Negation," Holograph and typescript, 1981. (Folder 26)
  - "Derivation of the Distributive From the Modular Law, with the Help of Probability Theory," Holograph and typescript, 1981. (Folder 27)
  - Letter to the editor, New Scientist, Holograph, typescript, and printed copy., 1981 February 12. (Folder 28)
    Includes article by John Sparkes, 1981 January 15, as well as another letter to the editor in response to John Sparkes' article by P. M. Sander and a letter from him to Karl Popper
  - Interview for Mondadori, Typescript, 1981 February or March. (Folder 29)
  - Letter to the editor, Free Inquiry, Printed copy and correspondence with Paul Kurtz, 1980-1981., 1981 Spring. (Folder 30)
    Includes the typescript and proofs of "A Secular Humanist Declaration," and a list of its signatories
  - "Toleration and Intellectual Responsibility," J. B. Morrell memorial address, University of York, York, England. See also "Duldsamkeit und intellektuelle Verantwortlichkeit," 1981 May 26, Draft, 1981 March 13.
    - Notes and outline (Box 225, Folder 1)
    - Holograph (Folder 2-5)
    - Typescript (in part holograph) (Folder 6-9)
    - Correspondence with Andrew Dunsire and William B. Morrell, 1980-1981 (Folder 10)
  - "Diritto d'errore: Conversazione con Karl Popper," Panorama, Interview by Corrado Augias. Holograph, typescript, printed copy, and correspondence, 1981 March 23. (Folder 11)
  - "The Importance of Critical Discussion: An Argument for Human Rights and Democracy," Speech, International Conference in Honor of Andrei Sakharov, New York City, New York, 1981 May 1-2.
    - Holograph (Box 226, Folder 1)
    - Typescript (Folder 2-8)
    - Printed copy, Free Inquiry (Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with Raymond Aron, David and Gregory Chudnovsky, and Ellen A. Marks (Folder 10)
  - "Lasst Theorien sterben anstatt Menschen," Stern, Proofs and printed copy., 1981 May 7. (Folder 11)
    Includes letter to the editor, 1982 July 30 (date written)
  - "Maximal Independence and Probabilistic Independence," Holograph and typescript, 1981 May 18. (Folder 12)
  - "Wissenschaft: Wissen und Nichtwissen," Speech, Zug, Switzerland. Notes, printed copies, clipping, and correspondence with Heinz A. Hertach (Stiftung Landis & Gyr), 1981 May 23. (Folder 13)
  - "Duldsamkeit und intellektuelle Verantwortlichkeit." Speech
    - Tubingen, Germany, (upon receiving the Leopold-Lucas Prize), 1981 May 26
      - Draft, 1980 December (Box 227, Folder 1)
      - Notes (Folder 2)
      - Holograph (Folder 3-4)
      - Typescript (Folder 5-11)
      - Typescript (Box 228, Folder 1-4)
      - Correction slip for publication in Toleranz, 1982 (Folder 5)
      - Correspondence with Peter Stuhlmacher, Josef Simon, Alfred Bosch and Reinhold Veit (Walter Eucken Institut), Freiherr von Gleichen, F. W. Lucas, and Otto Schulten, 1980-1983 (Folder 6)